cruisersforum.com 2019-05-18

# Cruisers & Sailing Forums

Social Knowledge L.L.C. (Social Knowledge) operates an online network of peer community websites (collectively referred to herein as the Community Websites). For a list of all Community Websites, please click [_here_](http://www.socialknowledge.com/).

Social Knowledge believes it is important to protect and respect the privacy of our members, users, and visitors. This Privacy Policy covers our treatment of personally identifiable information collected by Social Knowledge through our Community Websites.

We urge you to read this Privacy Policy so that you will understand both our commitment to you and your privacy, and how you can participate in that commitment.

**1\. Notice**

a. **_General._** In general, you can browse our Community Websites without telling us who you are or revealing any personal information about yourself. We will ask you when we need information that personally identifies you or allows us to contact you (Personal Information). Generally, this information is requested when you become a member of one of our Community Websites or contact us for information. We use your Personal Information for the following primary purposes:

i) To facilitate your experience on our Community Websites.

ii) To make our Community Websites easier for you to use by not having to enter information more than once.

iii) To help you quickly find information on the Community Websites.

iv) To alert you to special offers, updated information, and other new services from our company and affiliates.

b. **_Collected Information_**. Social Knowledge may collect information from you in several different ways including the following:

i) **_Registration._** In order to use the services offered by our Community Websites, you may be required to create an account with us. During the registration process, you are required to give certain contact information, including, but not limited to, your name, email address, birthday, gender, and mailing address. We use this information to contact you about the services on our Community Websites in which you have expressed interest and to facilitate future related services.

ii) **_Log Files._** As is true of most websites, Community Websites gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet Service Provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and movements around the site, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We do not link this automatically-collected data to personally identifiable information.

iii) **_Correspondence_**. If you send us personal correspondence, such as emails or letters, or if other users or third parties send us correspondence about your activities, we may collect such information into a file specific to you.

iv) **_Supplementation of Information._** In order to provide certain services to you, we may on occasion supplement the personal information you submitted to us with information from third-party sources.

c. **_Site Usage._** Social Knowledge may monitor your activities, preferences, and transactional data (such as your IP address) relating to your use of our Community Websites and/or services and log this information. This information may be used to diagnose Community Websites technical problems or problems with your account and to enhance your experience in using our Community Websites.

d. **_Cookies._** Cookies are data files that are written onto your computer by a website, and stay there unless they expire or are removed by you. Cookies enable us to recognize your computer when you revisit our Community Websites, and recall your Peer Community Network preferences to enhance your experience in using Community Websites. We do not use cookies to collect or use any information about your visits to other websites or otherwise collect any information from our Community Websites. Consult your browser Help menu to learn more about how you can configure your browser software to notify you when your computer receives a new cookie. Note that you may also be able to configure your browser to disable the creation of cookies entirely (although your full interactive use of Community Websites may be adversely impacted if you do this). We are not responsible for the use of cookies by third parties or how such parties may collect or use any information about your visits on our Community Websites. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by Community Websites only and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers or third parties.

e. **_Pixels Tags and Web Beacons_** Social Knowledge may use other industry standard technologies like pixel tags and web beacons to track your use of the Community Websites, or we may allow third parties to use these devices on our behalf. When you access the Community Websites, or open or click an email, pixel tags and web beacons generate a non-personally identifiable notice of that action. Pixel tags allow us to measure and improve our understanding of visitor traffic and behavior on the Community Websites, as well as give us a way to measure our promotions and performance. We may also utilize pixel tags and web beacons provided by our marketing and advertising partners for the same purposes.

f. **_Service-related Announcements._** We may send you strictly service-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email. Generally, you may opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature. If you do not wish to receive them, you have the option to deactivate your account.

**2\. Disclosure of Collected Information**

a. **_Information from the Site._** Social Knowledge will never disclose to non-affiliated third parties without your prior approval, your e-mail address, phone number, or other personally identifiable information, that we collect via Community Websites. However, we reserve the right to outsource certain activities to our business partners. In such case, we will disclose to these business partners only such information as is required to facilitate your transactions, and we will make every effort to have our business partners protect and refrain from disclosing your information to other third parties. Further, Social Knowledge will cooperate with official law enforcement inquiries, such as fraud investigations and subpoenas, and will disclose your information when necessary to comply with state and federal laws and regulations.

b. **_Information Disclosed for Direct Marketing._** From time to time, as marketing opportunities arise with trusted third-party companies, Social Knowledge may share your demographical information after a diligent review of the offers. Sharing information will be done only through reputable third parties who have safeguards in place. Social Knowledge screens all companies who request information and reserves the right of refusal on any opportunity if the third party does not meet certain standards. Social Knowledge will also cross market between its affiliated companies and others. However, our customers should be assured that at no time will personal e-mails be shared. Furthermore, you have the ability to opt-in for any third-party offers. For more information on our opt-in arrangement, please review the section entitled _Choice/Opt-Out._

c. **_Disclaimer._** We cannot ensure that all of your private communications and other personal information will never be disclosed in ways not otherwise described in this Privacy Policy. By way of example (without limiting the foregoing), we may be forced to disclose personal information to the government or third parties under certain circumstances, third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications, or users may abuse or misuse your personal information that they collect from Community Websites.

**3\. Security**

Social Knowledge is committed to ensuring that your registration information is protected while you are on our Site. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us from unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction, during transmission and once we receive it. Our goal is to provide a high quality service with the best possible online experience.

**4\. Enforcement**

If for some reason you believe Social Knowledge has not adhered to the principles of this Privacy Policy, please notify us by accessing the Contact Us link and submitting a request or ticket through the Social KnowledgeTM Community Support Center.

a. **_Limitations of Warranties and Remedies._** To the full extent allowed by law, SOCIAL KNOWLEDGE disclaims all warranties, terms or conditions, express or implied, either in fact or by operation of law, statutory or otherwise, including warranties, terms, or conditions of merchantability, fitness for a particular purpose, and warranty of noninfringement. SOCIAL KNOWLEDGE neither assumes nor authorizes any other person to assume for it any other liability in connection with SERVICES FROM SOCIAL KNOWLEDGE TROUGH THE COMMUNITY WEBSITES. liability OF SOCIAL KNOWLEDGE will not exceed the fee paid by the customer for the PURCHASE of the products. In no event will SOCIAL KNOWLEDGE be liable for any incidental, consequential, punitive, or special damages, including, without limitation, lost profits or revenues, even if SOCIAL KNOWLEDGE has, or should have had, any knowledge, actual or constructive, of the possibility of such damages.

b. **_Indemnification._** Each of the parties acknowledges and agrees that by entering into and performing its obligations under this Privacy Policy, Social Knowledge will not assume and should not be exposed to the business and operational risks associated with Your business. You agree to defend, indemnify, and hold harmless Social Knowledge and its officers and employees against any and all third party claims, suits, costs, losses liabilities and expenses of any kind (including reasonable attorneys fees) that Social Knowledge may incur arising out of or resulting from the use of the Community Websites or any of the services of Social Knowledge, the end user, or any other person.

c. **_Choice of Law and Venue_**. This agreement will be construed and governed in accordance with the laws of the state of Texas without application of choice-of-law provisions that would require application of the laws of another jurisdiction. By entering into this agreement, all parties irrevocably submit themselves to the exclusive jurisdiction of the state and federal courts in Dallas County, Texas with regard to any dispute relatING to this Privacy Policy or its enforcement. The parties also hereby waive any challenge to venue they may have to a lawsuit filed in a state or federal court in Dallas County, Texas, regarding a dispute between the parties relating to this Privacy Policy or its enforcement.

d. **_Severability._** If any provision of this Privacy Policy is found to be invalid, illegal, or unenforceable, the validity, legality and enforceability of any of the remaining provisions will not in any way be affected or impaired and a valid, legal, and enforceable provision of similar intent and economic impact will be substituted therefore.

e. **_Additional Provisions Regarding Liability._** The parties agree that the foregoing limitations will not be read so as to limit any liability to an extent that would not be permitted under applicable law and specifically will not limit any liability for gross negligence, intentional tortious or unlawful conduct, or damages for strict liability that may not be limited by law.

f. **_Notices._** Any notices or other communication required or permitted to be made or given by either Party pursuant to this Privacy Policy will be in writing, in English, and will be deemed to have been duly given when delivered if delivered personally or sent by recognized overnight express courier, to the address specified herein or such other address as Social Knowledge may specify in writing. All notices shall be sent to:

Social Knowledge LLC  
2600 E Southlake Blvd  
Suite 120-361  
Southlake, Texas 76092

**5\. Additional Information**

a. **_Links._** Our Community Websites may contain links to other sites. However, please be aware that Social Knowledge is not responsible for and cannot control the privacy policies of such other sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave the Community Websites, and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by our Community Websites.

b. **_Notification of Privacy Statement Changes._** We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time, and you may visit this page to learn of our revised Privacy Policy. All such changes shall be binding on you 14 calendar days after they are initially posted on our Community Websites unless you are a new user, in which case they are binding on you immediately.

c. **_Choice/Opt-Out._** Any customer may opt-out (or opt-in) at any time by accessing the Contact Us link and submitting a request or ticket through the Social KnowledgeTM Community Support Center.

d. **_Access to Personal Information._** If your personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer desire some or all of our services, you may correct, update or deactivate by accessing the Contact Us link and submitting a request or ticket through the Social Knowledge Community Support Center.

d. **_Business Transition._** In the event we go through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of our assets, your personally identifiable information will likely be among the assets transferred.

e. **_Contact Us._** If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, by accessing the Contact Us link and submitting a request or ticket through the Social KnowledgeTM Community Support Center.
